Guide to the Page Mill Road Co-ordinating Committee Records, 1965-1966
Department of Special Collections
Page Mill Road Co-ordinating Committee Records,
1965-1966
Special Collections M0970
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Lois Crozier Hogle, 1998
Biography
In the early sixties Stanford University was developing its Coyote Hill and Deer Park lands to the west of Junipero Serra Blvd. That project, together with the construction of Highway 280, created a need to widen Page Mill Road, particularly between Junipero Serra and 280. The proposed route ran along a creek past some homes and a historical site. The Page Mill Road Co-ordinating Committee, an early outgrowth of Committee for Green Foothills, worked to get the new road rerouted and a safe underpass constructed below Highway 280 for non-vehicular traffic. They also sought to complete a non- vehicular trail running roughly in the Page Mill corridor from Junipero Serra to the Skyline Road.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, committee meeting minutes, news clippings, flyers, photographs, blue prints, and publications.
Access terms
Allyn, Elizabeth H.; Bunneman, Oscar.; Ginzton, Artemas.; Gordon, Mary.; Grench, Norma.; Hansen, Ralph W.; Hogle, Lois Crozier.; Liukkonen, Reino.; Moffat, Mary.; Pearson, Enid.; Committee for Green Foothills.; Stanford University--Planning.; Palo Alto (Calif.)--History.; San Francisco Bay Region--Conservation of natural resources.
Container List
- Correspondence 1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence and minutes 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes 1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Correspondence and notes n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Membership List n.d. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Petition 1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- "Historical notes of interest surrounding Page Mill Road and Environs," by Ralph Hansen, Palo Alto Historian n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Material used in Page Mill - Serra Interchange report 1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Maps n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Reports: "A study of Page Mill Road" (3 copies), and "Proposal for a pathway system through the Page Mill - Junipero Serra Interchange." 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Correspondence 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Photographs (8 x 10, black and white glossies), 5 prints, 10 negatives, (in envelope marked "Esther Litton." n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Blueprint n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- News Clippings 1964 - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Stanford development 1960 - 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)